Guide to the James O'Shaughnessy Papers, 1888-1936
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
James O'Shaughnessy papers 1888-1936
O'Shaughnessy, James
1.3 linear feet Extent: 556 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00980
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2000.
Biographical Note
James O'Shaughnessy was an advertising executive whose posts included first Executive Manager of the American Association of Advertising Agencies from 1917-1928 and business manager at Liberty magazine from 1929-1931.
Collection Overview
Miscellaneous group of materials from various portions of advertising executive James O'Shaughnessy's professional life, including his speeches and writings; proofs of printed booklets; advertising studies; subject files; and ephemera. The materials relate mainly to his tenure as business manager of Liberty magazine, but also include the International Advertising Congress in Berlin 1929; the Outdoor Advertising Corporation; the O'Shaughnessy Advertising Company; the American Advertising Agents' Association; and a folder of articles on Knute Rockne. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History
Subject Headings
Liberty (New York (N.Y.: 1924); Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising-Congresses; American Advertising Agents' Association; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History; O'Shaughnessy Advertising Company; Outdoor Advertising Corporation; Rockne, Knute, 1888-1931; proofs (derivative objects)
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2000-0346
  - Liberty materials, surveys, writings, and other advertising files, 1919-1936 (Box 1)
    - Survey of Liberty readers, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Other Liberty materials and including Pathfinder magazine, 1926-1936, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Advertising Dictionary, undated (Box 1)
    - Splitting commissions file, 1919-1926 (Box 1)
    - Articles by O'Shaughnessy, 1928-1932 (Box 1)
  - Writings, sales talks, Knute Rockne clippings, and other advertising material, 1912-1936 (Box 2)
    - [Articles by O'Shaughnessy, ca. 1935-1936] (Box 2)
    - "Modern Advertising and Modern Printing," by O'Shaughnessy, Advertising and Printing, November 1912 (Box 2)
    - [Sales talks not used after I came], [Liberty magazine and Outdoor Advertising Incorporated], undated (Box 2)
    - Maps of Metropolitan NY market, [Outdoor Advertising Incorporated], undated (Box 2)
    - [Advertising samples-O'Shaughnessy Advertising Company] (Box 2)
    - Knute Rockne clippings, 1931 (Box 2)
    - O'Shaughnessy Advertising Company cancelled checks, 1916 (Box 2)
    - Weltreklame (World Advertising) Congress, Berlin, 1929, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Studies for Liberty and proofs of booklets for the American Advertising Agents' Association, 1888-1930 (Ovsz.) (Box 3)
    - Reports on Liberty magazine, 1927-1929 (Box 3)
    - Automobile study [for Liberty ], 1930 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Shipping Board advertisement survey, 1920 (Box 3)
    - [Galley proofs] of booklet, Proceedings [of the] Conference of the American Advertising Agents' Association, 1900 (Box 3)
    - Proofs of Proceedings [of the] Conference of the American Advertising Agents' Association, and of the Constitution and Bylaws of the American Advertising Agents' Association, 1888 (Box 3)